https://www.flow3d.com/privacy-policy/

Water & Environmental
Updated: May 21, 2018.Flow Science, Inc., a corporate entity incorporated in New Mexico, USA (hereinafter “FSI”), collects and processes Personal Data (as defined below) in the course of its business, including the Personal Data of people browsing its websites (the “Sites”).The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform all individuals from whom Personal Data is collected how FSI collects and uses such Personal Data and how you can control its use.This Privacy Policy applies to all Personal Data we collect about you. This will include information collected online (on https://www.flow3d.com/ or other FSI websites (“the Sites”), including mobile access) or offline, and information you provide us through your acquisition of FSI products or services, or when You request information or register for events related to FSI products or services (collectively, the “Services”). This Privacy Policy is applicable regardless of the means of collection.If you are reading this Privacy Notice as a visitor to one of the Sites, please note: each Site is subject to Terms of Use that can be found on such Site and are incorporated into this Privacy Policy. Your use of the Sites and any Personal Data You provide on the Sites are subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the applicable Terms of Use.This Privacy Policy was last updated on the date listed at the top of the page and applies from that date. We may occasionally amend this Privacy Policy and any changes will automatically be effective when published on the Sites. It is your responsibility to periodically review this Privacy Policy to ensure you understand these terms. You may retain a copy of this Privacy Policy for your records and any questions or concerns should be addressed as outlined below.We do not knowingly collect or process data from anyone under the age of thirteen (13) years old.What information do we collect?For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, “Personal Data” means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier, or to one or more factors specific to the identity of that person.Personal Data collected by FSI may include information such as title; first and last name; postal address; email address; telephone number(s); type of organization (company, school, university, etc.); organization name;  department; job title; industry and industry sub-industry sectors; machine information related to the device(s) from which licenses for FSI products will be served.We may also collect and process information obtained through your use of the Services or from the device you use to access the Services, including location information (via GPS signals sent by a mobile device (where enabled) or gathered from social media networks), sensor or IP address data from your device; information from cookies, web beacons or from the internet (including your IP address, browser type, operating system, domain name, access times, which pages you visit within the Sites and referring website addresses, how you use the Sites; you can find out more about how we use cookies below); recordings of any telephone calls for quality assurance and training purposes; and data regarding any unlicensed use of our software and services.In all cases, however, the Personal Data gathered is limited to data necessary for the purposes described herein.How do we use your information?Our primary purpose in the collection and use of your Personal Data is to provide you with the Services you request and for those purposes which we believe will help you optimize your use of the Services. In most cases, the lawful grounds for our use of your Personal Data will be that use: (i) is necessary to perform a contract with you (“Contract”); (ii) is based on your consent (“Consent”); or (iii) is necessary for our legitimate interests in carrying out our business, provided those interests are not outweighed by your rights and interests (”Legitimate Interests”). In certain instances, we may also have a legal obligation to use your Personal Data (“Legal Obligation”).Uses of Personal Data, as outlined in this Privacy Policy, are as outlined below and can be attributed to the following lawful grounds for processing by FSI:Necessary to perform a Contract:to provide the information, Services or support you request and related after-sales servicesto identify you and to contact you with product or service updates or training or support options related to products and services you’ve purchasedto manage our relationship with you and to carry out any related administrationWhere use of your Personal Data is based on your Consent, we will identify the purposes of processing such data and provide you with relevant information to make the processing fair and transparent.Necessary to carry out Legitimate Interests of FSI:to identify you for the purposes of ensuring compliance with the terms of license agreementsto send messages that are related or useful to the Services we provide youto compare your information for accuracy, and verify it with third parties as needed (such as for export compliance purposes)to carry out research, including market research, statistical research on site traffic, and sales and other commercial information to assist us in improving the Services we provide you and to tailor our sitesto identify you and verify that both the product and your use of it are appropriately licensed; if we believe that use of our software is unlicensed, we may also share that data with other software companies and organizations set up to counter software theft, as well as with law enforcementWith whom do we share your information and for what purposes?Legal Obligation:Though it is extremely unlikely event, we may be compelled to disclose your Personal Data in the interests of security in response to requests by law enforcement, regulatory or government authorities in the USA or any country where we have entities or affiliates.Delivery of the Services:We share your information, which may include Personal Data, with third parties who help deliver our products and services. Examples of third-party services we use include hosting of our web servers and delivery and monitoring of marketing initiatives. We also share your information to facilitate providing customer support services to resellers and distributors for our products (including affiliated companies) Where you provide Personal Data directly to one of our third-party service providers, the privacy policy and terms of use for that provider will be made available to you and will apply to the transaction. All FSI third-party service providers will only collect or have access to your Personal Data as needed to perform the service and may not use your data for any other purpose.We may use Google Analytics on our sites to gather statistics on site usage. This may involve the use of cookies, as outlined further below and Google’s privacy policy. Google may aggregate data it collects from these services together with data collected across other sites and services. Please read Google’s privacy policy and account settings with respect to data collected and used by Google across its services.Third-party linksThe Sites may contain links or references to third parties’ websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of third-party sites and services, even where we provide links or references for your convenience. Please read the policies and terms of use for any third party before using the Site or services.The servers used by third-party sites, including social media sites, may not be secure. Despite reasonable security measures taken by FSI and its partners and third-party service providers, use of the internet is not secure and unlawful or unauthorized access to private transmissions or data is possible.How do we protect your information?We have implemented reasonable and appropriate technical and organizational measures to guard against unauthorized or unlawful access to your Personal Data. While no system is completely secure, we believe the measures we have implemented reduce our potential vulnerability to a level appropriate to the types of Personal Data processed.Where is your information processed?Your Personal Data may be processed and stored on our servers or on the servers of our third-party service providers, in the United States or other countries where we or our service providers do business. This means that when we collect your Personal Data, we may transfer and process this data in any of these countries, including countries other than the country in which you reside. While your Personal Data may be transferred to countries with data protection laws that differ from those that apply in your country, and in some cases may be less protective, we will take steps to ensure that your Personal Data is protected in compliance with applicable data protection law and this Privacy Policy. We have implemented appropriate safeguards, including contractual obligations as required by law, with our third-party service providers and partners with whom we share Personal Data.CookiesWhat are cookies and why do we use them?A “cookie” is a small file placed on your hard drive by some of our web pages and used to track your activities on our Sites.  Sometimes we accomplish the same objectives using electronic images placed in the web page code, called pixel tags (also called a “clear GIFs” or “web beacons”) that can serve many of the same purposes as cookies. Web beacons may be used to track the traffic patterns of users from one page to another in order to maximize web traffic flow. Our third-party advertising service providers may also use Web Beacons to recognize you when you visit the Site and to help determine how you found the Site.We may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags and similar tracking technology (collectively, “Cookies”) to collect and use information about you to personalize your experience using the Sites, for various business analytics to improve our services, and to deliver interest-based advertising. We may also use similar technology in emails that we send you.Even if you are only browsing the Site, certain information (including computer and connection information, browser type and version, operating system and platform details and the time of accessing the Site) is automatically collected about you. This information will be collected every time you access the Site and it will be used for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy.If you would like more information about the practices described above, and to know your choices, click here: //networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp.How to manage use of CookiesYou may delete and block all Cookies from this Site, but parts of the site may not work as expected. You can also reduce the information that Cookies collect from your device. An easy way of doing this is often to change the settings in your browser. Here is a good resource for learning how to do this: www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/. If you take this step, be aware that your use of the Sites may be adversely affected and your experience of this and other sites that use Cookies to enhance or personalize your experience may be adversely affected.Marketing communicationsAs outlined above, we (or, in some cases, a third-party service provider or partner on our behalf) may use your Personal Data to send you marketing information in accordance with the marketing preferences you select when providing your information. You may opt-out of receiving electronic marketing communications at any time by the following means:click the “unsubscribe” link located in each electronic communication; orcontact us at compliance@flow3d.com with “remove” in the subject line.Please remember that if you change your marketing preferences, it may take a short time for those preferences to become effective. By opting out of marketing communications, you will still continue to receive communications (including emails) related to your User Account and the Services, including product updates, trainings, and communications related to billing, maintenance, and support.How long do we keep your information?We retain your Personal Data only as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, or as permitted or required by applicable law. At the end of the applicable retention period, we will securely delete your Personal Data, or, if deletion is not possible (for example, because your Personal Data has been stored in back-up archives), we will securely store your Personal Data separate from any further processing until deletion is possible.Data Subject RightsYou have the following data protection rights, as may be amended from time to time by applicable law:If you wish to access, correct, update or request deletion of the Personal Data we retain about you, you can do so at any time by contacting us at compliance@flow3d.com.If you are a resident of the European Union, you can object to processing of your Personal Data, request that we restrict processing of your Personal Data, or request portability of your Personal Data, as outlined by the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679. You may make any request under this section by contacting us at compliance@flow3d.com.If we have collected and process your Personal Data based on your consent, you may withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your Personal Data conducted in reliance upon lawful processing grounds other than consent (such as processing based on Contract or Legitimate Interests).You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.How do you contact us?If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or FSI privacy practices related to the Services, we encourage you to contact us directly at compliance@flow3d.com.
Subscribe to flow-3d news
Newsletter Registration Form
Connect with us on SocialFacebookInstagramLinkedInTwitterYouTube
Flow ScienceA Message to the FLOW-3D Community
About Us
Blog
Careers
Contact Us
Events
Partners
Press Releases
Data Subject Access Request
FLOW-3D and TruVOF are registered trademarks of Flow Science, Inc. in the USA and other countries.COPYRIGHT 2000 – 2020 FLOW SCIENCE, INC. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.
Request More Information
FLOW-3D AM WELD Request Info
First Name
*
Last Name
*
Company/Institution
*
What product are you interested in?
FLOW-3D AM
FLOW-3D WELD
What additive manufacturing processes do you want to simulate?
What laser welding processes do you want to simulate?
I am interested in:
Yes, please sign me up to receive email news.
Privacy
*
I acknowledge I have read and I accept the Privacy Policy under which my Personal Data will be used by Flow Science. *
reCAPTCHA
Request Info
If you are human, leave this field blank.
Schedule a one-on-one demo with a water & environmental applications engineer:
Yes, please sign me up to receive email news.
Privacy
*
I acknowledge I have read and I accept the Privacy Policy under which my Personal Data will be used by Flow Science. *
reCAPTCHA
Request Pricing
If you are human, leave this field blank.
I am interested in:
Yes, please sign me up to receive email news.
Privacy
*
I acknowledge I have read and I accept the Privacy Policy under which my Personal Data will be used by Flow Science. *
reCAPTCHA
Request CFD Services
If you are human, leave this field blank.
Schedule a one-on-one demonstration with a metal casting simulation engineer:
Yes, please sign me up to receive email news.
Privacy
*
I acknowledge I have read and I accept the Privacy Policy under which my Personal Data will be used by Flow Science. *
reCAPTCHA
Request Pricing
If you are human, leave this field blank.
This site uses cookies:
Find out more.Okay, thanks
